Frances Gillmor papers, 1910-1993 (Bulk 1930-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VI: Research Notes, 1930s-1970s
  - Subseries IV: Spain.
    - Balearic Isles; Moors and Christians and gigantes (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Barcelona (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Cáceres (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Cartagena; Semana sante, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
    - Cartagena; Semana sante, [three tape reels], 1960 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Concentaina (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Cuenca; Moors and Christians from Espinosa-Rael collection (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Elche (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
    - Elche [two tape reels] (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Gergal (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Guadeloupe [Spain] (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Jerez de la Frontera (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Lerida (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Lorca (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Madrid (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
    - Málaga (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Melvizar (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Muchamiel (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Onteniente (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Pamplona (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Pontevedra, Puente Arnelas and Portazuela [?] (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Proveda de la Sierra; Moors and Christians (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Puente Genil (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Quéntar (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Rouda (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Santiago de Compostela (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Valencia; folklore including Corpus Christi procession, moros, gigantes, etc. (Box 32, Folder 11-12)
    - Valencia (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - Vélez Benaudalla (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Villagarcía (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Villajoyosa (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Zamora (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Spain. Sección Femenina (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Audio Materials, 1950s-1970s.
  - Subseries I: Oral Histories and Interviews.
    Tape reels and cassettes containing oral histories, primarily from residents of Arizona. Some of the materials in the series Research Notes also include audio recordings made during Gillmor’s field work.
    - Larry Toledo / Raimundo Duran (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - John Hollingsworth interview, July 14, 1969. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Oral history of Tucson, Arizona (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Interview by Fernando Santa Cruz (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Western and German songs (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Interview with Jean Goodwin, railroad telegrapher (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Benson, Arizona oral history, 1971. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Tucson, Arizona oral history recordings (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Tucson, Arizona oral history recordings (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries II: Field Recordings.
    - Mass sung at San Xavier del Bac, Saturday, May 1, 1971. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Interviews with various individuals in Mexico (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified / unlabelled tape reels (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Gypsies in [S______?]; Spain (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Salatitán, Mexico (Box 37, Folder 2-3)
    - Vocotan; San Juan Ocotan (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Almuñecar, Spain (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Cartagena, Spain, Semana santa; Alcoloy, Moors and Christians (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Atemejac del Valle [Jalisco, Mexico]; recording made on August 1, 1964 of a rehearsal of La conquista, August 1, 1964. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Interview in Michoacán, Mexico [?] (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Spanish-language interview; place, date, subject not identified (Box 38, Folder 3)
- Series VIII: Photographs and Visual Materials, 1903-1991.
  - Subseries I: Personal and Family, 1903-1991.
    Photographs of Frances Gillmor and her family members, friends and associates. Additional photographs of Gillmor are included in the Biographical Materials series.
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor’s family: grandparents; aunts and uncles (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor’s family: parents (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor, 1903-1923. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor, 1923-1939. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor, ca. 1940-1991. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor, 1940-1991. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Frances Gillmor, and her friends and associates, 1930’s-1980’s. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Frances Gillmor in Europe (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Frances Gillmor in Mexico (Box 40, Folder 4-6)
  - Subseries II: Field and Research Materials.
    Photographs, slides and negatives taken during research trips and fieldwork. Includes some slides of French, Greek, and Roman architecture used in one of Gillmor’s courses. The photographs and slides primarily depict festival scenes or performances of folk plays in Spain and Mexico. This series includes five oversize manuscript chronological charts created by Gillmor to establish Aztec chronology. The charts compare dates and events as recorded in several codices.
    - Color slides of Patagonia, Arizona; Tucson, Arizona; Crete, Greece (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Crete, Greece (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Mexico, photographs and negatives (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Unmounted slides, chiefly Spain (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Negatives (unsorted) (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Italy and France (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
    - Two printing plates of Aztec pictographs used in offset printing of poster announcing Gillmor liberal arts lecture (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Mexico (Box 43)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Mexico (Box 44)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Spain (Box 45)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Spain (Box 46)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Spain (Box 47)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Tucson, Arizona, El volador, 1970; Mexico, 1970 (Box 48)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Greece; Episcopal Church in Mexico (Box 49)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 and 35 mm. formats, Mexico; “Navajo Country;” Aztec bird pictures (Box 50)
    - Kirkefest og folkeliv [?] [film reels] (Box 51)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Greece and Italy (for Humanities course?) (Box 52)
    - Color transparencies, 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 format, Mexico (Box 53)
    - Five oversize manuscript chronological charts of early Mexican history (Box 54)
    - Midgetape® tape recorder / player; operating manual (Box 55)